## MAJOR GLENN S. CANTY

#### HEALTHCARE OPERATIONS EXECUTIVE

Active-Secret Security Clearance Stafford, VA 22556 \* (803) 840-5864

glennscanty@gmail.com

\* www.linkedin.com/in/glenn-canty-a58401157

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

A Healthcare Operations and Strategy Executive with over 23 years of expertise, in delivering high-impact business strategies, managing high performing teams and aligning business objectives with the mission. Initiative and metrics-oriented—versed in strategic planning, operation course of action development, and revenue growth both organically and through acquisitions. Servant leader committed to developing and broadening other healthcare operations leaders through experiences and lessons learned. Prior background as a Healthcare Administrator for multiple military healthcare facilities in the U.S. and abroad, currently holds a Secret Security Clearance.

- Strategic Vision Planning
- Regional Management
- Change Leadership
- Revenue Optimization
- Inter-Agency Collaboration
- Purposeful Decision Making
- Physician Relations
- Cost Reduction
- Risk Mitigation

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Chief Patient Administrator (Army National Guard) | Arlington, VA

July 2022 - Current

Deputy COO for Clinical Operations, Lead for Patient Administration, Advisor to Chief Medical Officer (Army National Guard), National HIPAA Privacy and Compliance Officer, Lead for Electronic Health Record – Major Advises Chief Medical Officer on all Patient Administration related issues and provides technical guidance to 54 State, Territory, and District Army National Guard (ARNG) senior medical staffs. Medical Electronic Data for Care History and Readiness Tracking (MEDCHART) and Electronic Health Record (EHR) subject matter expert responsible for personnel access and module provisioning for all service component soldiers and support staff. Develops ARNG-specific policy and guidance related to Service Treatment Record (STR) and Protected Health Information (PHI) management, disability evaluation processing, and Patient Administration (PAD) related medical readiness issues. Serves as senior PAD subject matter expert, HIPAA Privacy Officer and TRICARE Liaison Officer between ARNG and Active Army; advocates for Guard-specific issues.

- Transform tactical and Garrison Healthcare Organizations to proactive and results driven, improving training and software participation
- Oversee hiring and credentialing of clinical staff, as well as the training and supervision of non-clinical personnel
- Monitor records compliance to all medical standards and arrange continuing education on policy and procedures
- Create and amend Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs) for claims submission guidelines and medical readiness
- Build high-performing teams and platforms that are grounded in service, resolve and patient/employee satisfaction

### Student, Command and General Staff College | Fort Leavenworth, KS

Aug 2021 - June 2022

## Graduate Student - Major

Was trained and developed for Unified Land Operations in a Joint, interagency, intergovernmental, and multinational operational environment and was able to build on the art of science of the Profession of Arms in support of Army operational requirements. Embedded and partnered with 1200 students in an Advanced Operations Course (AOC) highlighting advanced U.S. and Foreign Military policy and threats. Attained a Masters of Operational Studies (MOS) as the Small Group Medical Planner and Health and Fitness Coordinator.

- Extensive learning in six academic departments Department of Army Tactics (DTAC), the Department of Logistics and Resource Operations (DLRO), the Department of Joint, Interagency and Multinational Operations (DJIMO), Department of Command and Leadership (DCL), Department of Military History (DMH), and the Department of Distance Education (DDE)
- Attuned to the complexity of the operating environment and consider the impact of culture on military operations

- Used historical context to inform professional military judgment
- Analyzed joint operations fundamentals/ doctrine with the capabilities, limitations and considerations of joint forces/unified action partners in joint operations to develop an operational approach and course of action

## Regional COO/Senior Administration Officer for Patient Movement | Scott AFB, IL

July 2019 - June 2021

# National Director of Patient Movement and Director of Medical Administration, USTRANSCOM/ Executive Officer -Captain

Senior Patient Movement Operations Officer (PMOO) who supervised the subordinate PMOO and Patient Movement Controllers (PMC). Responsible for all reports required and any additional reports requested by the Theatre Patient Movement Requirements Center (TPMRC)Chief and USTRANSCOM Command Surgeon. Directed operational and managerial aspects of the 24-hour Patient Movement Requirements Center. Primary liaison with the Department of Defense (DoD) Medical Treatment Facilities (MTF), Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), civilian and other governmental/ non-governmental agencies on patient movement (PM) operations. Communicated with senior officials of Department of Defense Medical Treatment Facilities, Department of Veterans Affairs, and required external agencies regarding patient movement (PM) operations. Responsible for coordinating patient moves while considering multi-modal transportation assets and available resources at the receiving Primary Receiving Center (PRC)/ Federal Coordinating Center (FCC).

- Review, compile and provide region wide data specifically focusing on improvements and area of opportunity
- Provided resolution to issues/complaints in patient travel and emergency evacuations
- Interviewed, onboarded, trained and counseled new Chiefs and subordinates
- Monitored and analyzes trends involving census, acuity, staff resources and changes in patient population and recommends budgets for areas of assigned responsibility
- Collaborated effectively with other department officers, administrative personnel and physicians in accordance with the Organization's mission and values

## Aide-De Camp (Executive Secretary) to Major General | Fort Sam Houston, TX

May 2018 - June 2019

Secretary to President, Medical Center of Excellence/ Servant Leader/ Travel Planner/Coordinator - Captain Executive Secretary to the Commanding General (CG), Health Readiness Center of Excellence. Responsible for the planning, preparation, and execution of all official travel, social engagements, conferences, and speeches. Assisted in the scheduling of near, short, and long-range official events and the synchronization with higher, subordinate and external agencies involving the Commanding General. Maintained continuous communication with all elements while traveling, allowing the Commanding General to simultaneously influence multiple strategic and joint events. Managed the Commanding General's calendar, funds, property, and other affairs related to his official duties. Ensures voice and digital communications are maintained at all times.

- Mobilized and served as the Executive Assistant to the Commanding General for 10,000 person military personnel
- Impeccable ability to communicate and coordinate between multiple agencies and departments
- Managed and directed day-to-day activity, long range calendar and all travel requirements
- Supervised members of the General's personal staff
- Maintained yearly schedule of events, speaking engagements and prepared talking points for CG presentations

### Company Commander | Fort Sam Houston, TX

May 2017 - May 2018

## Director/Deputy Commanding Officer/Advocate / Disciplinarian / Educator - Captain

Commander for a multidisciplinary medical training company of Initial Entry Trainee (IET) and prior service Soldiers consisting of Multiple Military Occupational Skills, and Officer Areas of Concentration producing courses, consisting of more than 50 Staff and 200 Soldiers. Responsible for developing and maintaining high standards of discipline while continuing and completing the Soldier transformation process. Provided mission command, logistical and operational support, and ensures the health and welfare of all Soldiers; trains and qualifies over 700 Soldiers annually. Provided training mentorship and leader development for one executive officer, a first sergeant, eight platoon sergeants/drill sergeants and one operations sergeant. Fostered a positive command climate that educates Soldiers, encourages reporting, and safeguards victim's rights.

- Responsible for the overall unit's mission, command, professional development, logistics and combat readiness
- Developed and implemented operation policy and processes to exceed command goals

- Facilitated monthly meetings to develop strategies for soldier retention and Physical Fitness max percentages
- Addresses inquires and complaints relating to Sexual Harassment Sexual Assault Response Program (SHARP) complaints and Suicide Awareness
- Developed and implanted operational security policy to foster and maintain a safe environment for soldiers

# Executive Assistant to The Medical Service Corps Chief (Major General) | Fort Sam Houston, TX May 2015 – May 2017

# Secretary to President, Medical Service Corps/ Servant Leader/ Travel Planner/Coordinator

Responsible for executing all actions on behalf of the Deputy Corps Chief in support of the Chief of the Medical Service Corps(MSC). Actively supports over 10,000 active duty and reserve component officers in the MSC; provides real-time updates to the corps on all MSC professional development web-based platforms; develops and publishes historical documents highlighting training, accomplishments, and advances in all 27 Areas of Concentrations and Specialties within the MSC; provides analysis and planning perspectives for the funding and execution of Junior Officer Week, Iron Majors Week, and MSC Branch Day support activities.

- Responsible for the overall planning of Corps level Officers functions and corporate events
- Facilitated monthly meetings, correspondence and calendar events for Corps Chief and Deputy Corps Chief in line with campaign plans and US Army Medical Department initiatives
- Addresses inquires and complaints relating to all Medical Service Corps career accessions, leadership development and Senior Officer branching.
- Partnered with The Army Surgeon General staff ensuring collaboration between general officers including events and travel

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Operational Studies | Command and General Staff College Bachelor of Applied Sciences | Wayland Baptist University Associate Applied Sciences | Wayland Baptist University

#### **AFFILIATIONS**

Member | American College of Healthcare Executives (ACHE) Member | National Association of Health Services Executives (NAHSE)

#### SPECIALIZED MILITARY TRAINING

Patient Administration Course
Combat Medic Course
Physical Therapy Technician Course
Basic Healthcare Enlisted Leader Course
Senior Healthcare Enlisted Leader Course
Army Retention Course
Drill Sergeant Course
Air Assault Course
Company Grade Officer Health Care Administrator Course
Field Grade Officer Healthcare Administrator Course

## **NOTABLE MILITARY AWARDS**

Meritorious Service Medal
Army Commendation Medal
Global War on Terrorism Service Medal
Korean Defense Serve Medal
Military Outstanding Volunteer Service Medal
Leadership Award Recipient
Enlisted Leader of the Year